Hello professor, today let's analyze Criterion 2.4.8, Location (Position),
that is, provide information about the location
of the user in a series of web pages.
Let's analyze the techniques
sufficient and additional ones.
Let's go to see them in general first
and then we will see them specifically with tests.
The first sufficient technique
is to provide the user with a breadcrumb.
The second is to provide the user with a sitemap.
The third is to indicate your current location
in the navigation bars
of web pages.
The fourth is to identify
a relationship with a page,
with a larger amount of pages.
This technique has a sub-technique
ie the use of the "link" element, the element "link"
that is, those tags that are not visible to the user, such as "meta" tags.
Instead the additional techniques are two,
the first is to provide in a pdf document
a header and a footer.
The second, instead, consists in specifying
in a pdf document, the page number.
Now let's see the application
of sufficient techniques.
This first page shows us a brief
description of my Criterion and the list
enough techniques that now
we will go to see specifically.
Here we see the application of the first
technique, breadcrumb navigation,
which shows the user its location
within a series of web pages.
A breadcrumb trail displays
also the path it has taken
the user to reach a certain web page
and always allows the user
to go back to the previous pages.
Here we have an example, if the user
wants to go to a certain page
of the website, for example the description
of the "Scala dei Turchi" for example,
by clicking this button the user
he will be told which page he is on
and has a chance to return
on the previous pages and also
on the intial page, on the Home page.
This is the code that allows us
the application of the first technique,
ie breadcrumb navigation
It is simply a list it contains
the location where the user is located
and moving through the various sections
we find a list that is modified
where the position is always contained
of the user, but which allows the user
to return to the previous pages,
as we see in all these pages.
Now, let's see the application of the
second technique, provide a sitemap.
A sitemap is a web page that
allows links to
different sections that can be
present on a site.
To give the possibility that this
sitemap is complete,
each web page listed in the sitemap,
it must contain a link to it.
The sitemap serves several purposes,
provides a whole overview
of the web page,
helps users understand what it contains
the whole site and how it is organized.
And besides, it's very easy to understand.
Now let's see an example, each section
of a website, has a link
to the sitemap.
The sitemap is structured like this,
and the various sections listed lead,
by clicking on the corresponding section.
This is the code that allows us
the application of the second criterion,
ie the sitemap.
The sitemap is structured like this,
that is, a list that contains
inside it some words
which are clickable, which lead
to the various sections of the site.
Each section, inside it, in the bar
of navigation, contains
a link to the sitemap.
This is very important
to allow the user to understand
its position within the web page.
Now let's see the application
of the third technique, that is, indicate
to the user, its position inside
navigation bars.
The goal of this technique
it's really helping the user by providing
information about its current
location in the navigation bars.
This technique is very useful when
web pages must be
in a specific order.
We can provide you with yours
position through an icon, a text
or by changing the state of the item.
In my case I put a colored
background to the section or page
where the user is located.
Let's go see an example, here
we have our own navigation bar
by section or page
in which the user, the box,
the button where the section is indicated,
will light up, turn blue.
This way the user will know which one
section of the page is located.
This is the code that allows us
the application of the third technique,
that is to indicate to the user, his
current location inside
navigation bars.
This is the code. A div that contains
inside, clickable words,
which lead to the various sections
of the page. In this case,
description, photos and videos.
To indicate to the user his
position, I used a class,
in this case, "active", to indicate
to the user who clicks, the button
will turn blue.
In this case it will be very intuitive
for the user, understand in what position
of the page, he is.
In fact the button will turn blue if
is in the home, it will turn blue
if it is in the description section,
in the photo section, in the video section
and so on.
Now, let's see the application of the
fourth technique, one of the last
sufficient techniques,
which identifies the relationship of a
web page with a larger collection
of web pages.
The goal of this technique is,
allow users to
identify what relationship is present
between the current web page and others
web pages of the same collection,
for example on the same website.
In some cases, this can be done
programmatically, for example
using the "rel" attribute
of the "link" element in HTML.
In other cases the necessary
information are included in the title
of the web page, as in the example
of the "Descrizione Criterio" page.
Indeed the title is "Criterio 2.4.8 Location",
with "Tecniche Sufficienti" next, that
identifies as, the current page
is linked to other pages.
Now let's see the use of "meta" tags
which serve to provide
additional information,
like the author, the description,
the topic covered on the page
and also the language.
We also have the option to use
the "rel" attribute, which allows you to
indicate what relationship there is between a
current document and the document of
destination "link".
We also remember the use of the tag
"link" that allows us to link
of a current page, such as
for an example, with a CSS file or a
page with author information.
However, we must remember that
to work, the "rel" attribute must
always be accompanied
from the "href" attribute, which identifies
the destination.
These "link" tags are fully
satisfied with the use of the
technique "H59", which implements the use
"link" tags and navigation
tools.
The goal of this technique is
describe how "link" tags can
provide location information
of an HTML page, within a
series of extensive web pages or help
the user to locate the content.
The value of the "rel" attributes indicates
what kind of relation is there,
and the "href" attribute provides a
link to current document
with that relation.
The more "link" tags there are, the more they will be
present information.
Programmatically I have entered
the "link" tags with the "rel" attribute,
"href" and a "title" attribute, which are for
provide additional information.
For example, I added the main
page, ie "index" and
the previous page.
The "rel" attribute that identifies the
type of connection,
the "href" attribute that is used to identify
the corresponding resource
and the "title" attribute which provides a title.
Finally, remember that the "link" tags
and "meta", very often do not generate
no change in the eyes
of the user, but they are very important
for search engines and browsers.
This is the code allows us
the application of the last two
sufficient techniques, that is
"Identify the relation of a
web page with a larger collection"
and the use of "link" tags.
Here, in fact, on this page, we see
the use of "link" tags and in the
page "index" we see the use
some "meta" tags and an appropriate title
indicating the relation of the current
page, in this case "index" with
the other pages present.
Now let's see the last two techniques
additional, the first is "provide a
header and footer" in
pdf documents.
The goal of this technique is
to help users understand where
they are found in a pdf document.
In this case by providing
a header and a footer.
Headers and footers help
to make the content more
understandable, providing information
repeated consistently.
In this case we see, as for
example can be a title of the
document, a current chapter,
a general information about the author
in the header. The Decameron,
Chapter VII, Giovanni Boccaccio,
poet and author of the Decameron...
The second additional technique
specifies the page numbering
in pdf documents, that is simply,
the goal of this technique is
help users understand where to
find, in a pdf document.
A page number can be entered,
for example, 1, and 2 on the second page
or a date.